In this next segment, I want to talk to you about the trailer hitch lighting.
The trailer has lights so you've got to be able to plug it in to your vehicle lights.
You have brake lights, turn signals, so you can warn the people behind you when you're stopping.
This vehicle came with a towing package installed on it so because it came with a towing package it also has trailer brakes.
This is the kind of plug in that you're going to have for trailer brakes.
It's larger and more round and it's got like a 5 pin plug in, 6 pin plug in inside.
So when you plug it in, you're trailer brakes will actually operate off of the vehicle itself.
Some vehicles you're going to have to wire the brakes yourself.
You're going to have to wire the lights yourself.
The, like possibly on a Ford Ranger, you can buy a plug and it plugs into your wiring harness so you don't have to splice any wires but some vehicles don't come with that capability, so what you're going to have to do is you're going to have to actually splice into the brake lamp wiring inside of the trunk of the vehicle.
When we're talking about trailer lights, I've already shown you one type of trailer light, where it plugs in and it's integrated in with the braking system of the trailer but if you don't have a vehicle with trailer brakes or a trailer with trailer brakes this is probably the plug that you're going to be seeing.
It's a little four, flat, four pin plug.
It's pretty common, most vehicles have them.
This is what's going to be on your vehicle and it's very simple to use.
You can't go wrong, there's one pin that's different than the rest and you'll just simply plug it in to your trailer, like so, when you're ready to go.
So when you hook it up make sure you plug your lights in so the people behind you can see what you're doing.